Hull University Archives: Papers of Denzil Dean Harber
Papers of Denzil Dean Harber
1932-1946
2 boxes
Hull University Archives
U DDH
Denzil Harber was born at 25 Fairmile Avenue, Streatham, on 25 Jan 1909. He was active in British Trotskyist politics in the 1930s and 1940s, firstly in the Militant Group. He later became secretary of the Revolutionary Socialist League and then a member of the Revolutionary Communist Party. Denzil Harber died at the age of 55 on 31 Aug 1966.
paragraph 2
The collection includes files of photocopied documents relating to resolutions, statements and correspondence of the Revolutionary Socialist League, and photocopied records of the Workers' International League, the Revolutionary Communist Party, as well as a number of other parties.
another paragraph
U DDH/1 Various parties, 1932-1938
U DDH/2-12 Revolutionary Socialist League, 1939-1941
U DDH/13 Workers' International League, 1938-1942
U DDH/14 Revolutionary Communist Party, 1944-1946
Access will be given to any accredited reader
MSS.151, Modern Records Centre, University of Warwick [GB 0152]
Copied with the permission of Julian Harber
Another paragraph
Papers of Jock Haston (records of the Revolutionary Communist Party) [U DJH]
Other repositories:
Papers of Henry Sara and Frank Maitland (MSS.15); Ken Tarbuck (MSS.75); Harry Wicks (MSS.102); Colin Barker/International Socialism papers (MSS.152); and Reg Groves (MSS.17), Modern Records Centre, University of Warwick [GB 0152]
Entry in Modern political papers subject guide
John Archer, Trotskyism in Britain 1931-37 (PhD Thesis, Central London Polytechnic, 1979) Reginald Groves, The Balham Group: how British Trotskyism began (Pluto Press Ltd, 1974)
- Photocopy of file '1932 - 38', 1932-1938; 1 file; Hull University Archives; U DDH/1
  Includes papers published by the Independent Labour Party, the Communist Party of Great Britain and the Revolutionary Socialist League
- Photocopy. Revolutionary Socialist League, 1939 - 1942; 1 file; Hull University Archives; U DDH/2
  Internal documents
- Photocopy. Revolutionary Socialist League, 1940-1943; 1 file; Hull University Archives; U DDH/3
  Executive Committee/Central Committee minutes, constitution and papers circulated
- Photocopy. Revolutionary Socialist League, 1941; 1 file; Hull University Archives; U DDH/4
- Photocopy. Revolutionary Socialist League, 1942-1943; 1 file; Hull University Archives; U DDH/5
- Photocopy. Revolutionary Socialist League, 1942-1943; 1 file; Hull University Archives; U DDH/6
- Photocopy. Miscellaneous documents, largely of the Left Fraction of the Revolutionary Socialist League, 1942-1943; 1 file; Hull University Archives; U DDH/7
  Includes resolutions, statements and correspondence
- Photocopy. Miscellaneous documents of the Revolutionary Socialist League, 1942-1943; 1 file; Hull University Archives; U DDH/8
- Photocopy. Miscellaneous documents of the Revolutionary Socialist League, 1943-1944; 1 file; Hull University Archives; U DDH/9
  Includes resolutions, statements and correspondence (including much Militant material)
- Photocopy. Revolutionary Socialist League: Workers' International League Fusion, Mar 1944; 1 file; Hull University Archives; U DDH/10
- Photocopy. Revolutionary Socialist League 'Expulsions of right wing', Feb-Oct 1943; 1 file; Hull University Archives; U DDH/11
- Photocopy. Revolutionary Socialist League - Workers' International League, 1940-1943; 1 file; Hull University Archives; U DDH/12
  Correspondence
- Photocopy. Workers' International League, 1938-1942; 1 file; Hull University Archives; U DDH/13
  Includes statements, constitution and correspondence
- Photocopy. Revolutionary Communist Party, 1944-1946; 1 file; Hull University Archives; U DDH/14
  Includes internal documents, bulletins and correspondence